Friends, my name is Anil Rajpat,
MBA Finance, Founder, Family Fund Financial Services. I have been
working in the corporate sector for 14 years.
Today, I am presenting to you a
student travel insurance
policy related to student education. It is an
ICICI Loard General Insurance policy. The
plan is called the Globe
Protector Overseas Student Individual
Insurance Policy. This is an
education-related
policy for students who go abroad for studies.
Watch the full video. If you like the video, please like, share and
subscribe to Anil Raj Files. Why should you have a student travel
insurance policy? When you
go abroad for studies,
your education is very expensive.
If you fall ill there or have an accident, the
expenses incurred there are very expensive. Firstly,
when an Indian goes abroad, he
goes on loan most of the time. And on top of that,
if he falls ill there, his
expenses become even more expensive. They are in dollars.
In all these expenses,
along with the education, the parents' money is also involved.  Expenses can
also be quite expensive, so if you
have a travel insurance policy,
you can avoid this expense, plus there's
peace of mind for your parents as well. Now, what benefits will you get
from taking this ICICI Loard policy?
Firstly, their
tie-up is with United Health Group and Falak,
which have Worldwide Cashless
Hospitals. Secondly, wherever
you go to study abroad, the
university you go to
demands insurance to check whether
you have insurance or
not. This is a tailor-made plan,
designed according to the type of plan required by the university. Plus, you
get good coverage, like campus visit,
sponsor protection, study interruption,
and many more features, which
I will explain in detail later. These are all the features that are
available in this policy. The
first one is stay-related coverage.
What coverage will be there during your stay there? The first one will be
personal liabilities, for example, because of you.  If an
accident occurs and a third
person overseas suffers
loss or dies due to the accident, then
you will be liable. At that
time,
your insurance cover, which can range from $500
to $5 lakh, will be covered.
The second policy is
personal accident. If your own
student meets with an accident, then if there is
death in the accident, then you will
get 100% of your insurance cover.
If there is no death in the accident,
but for example, your joint breaks
or is damaged, then you will get an off sum of Rs. 70.
If your thumb is damaged, then you will get it at Rs. 10. If a finger is damaged, then you will
get it at Rs.
5. If an index finger is damaged, then you will get it at Rs.
10. If
you are damaged, then you will get it at Rs. 50. If a
leg is damaged, then you will get it at Rs. 70. So, the
dismemberment that happens in different accidents is a certain portion and that will be
covered in this accident policy.
Apart from this, study  There can be an interruption,
for example, if your immediate family
member or your sponsor, who can be your
close family member or a third
party, or even a third person, falls
ill for a month or more or dies,
and you have to leave your studies and come to India, then whatever
tuition fees you have, whatever
remaining tuition fees will be waived, let's
talk about spinner production
spinner. Many times you
get a spinner for your studies, who can be your relatives, or even
a third person.
Now, if they die or fall ill, then the
remaining tuition fees will be
waived here. Regarding
travel-related coverage, here is the
total loss of check-in package. If, while you are
travelling and you are in an airline,
your baggage gets lost due to the fault of the airline, then
if you have one bag, then
100% of the money will be a special sum.
I will explain in detail later how much amount you get from which second to that.  This
is the amount you will
get in case of loss of baggage, but if there are two bags, then you will
get it for Rs. 50. Let's talk about loss of
passport. If you
lose your passport while traveling, then all the expenses incurred in making a new passport,
making a duplicate passport,
or making a fresh passport will be
reimbursed. You
should take Sese Labad's Global Traveler Overseas Individual Student Insurance policy because it is cost-effective.
If you purchase the policy from abroad,
you will have to
pay the premium in dollars, which will be expensive.
In India, you will have to pay the premium in Indian Rupees only,
and it will be comparatively cheaper.
Secondly, there is the admission criteria.
When you take admission in a university abroad,
travel
insurance is mandatory there. So, there are
excellent
products to fulfill that need. Along with this, it is also
providing holistic coverage. As you have seen, if you suffer a
lot of baggage loss, liabilities,
study interruption, or death of the student, then there are
many good features in this policy.  The
reason why you should
take this policy of ICICI Lampard is that in this thing you
get health cover, suppose if there is an
accident and you have to go to the hospital
or due to some illness you have to
go to the hospital, then whatever medical
assistance is required, be it X-ray or any
other test, then you should
talk to the company's TPA first and after
knowing what things are covered, you will get this
health cover there, whether it is
related to illness or accident. Now let's
see the feature wise study interruption, which
I also told earlier, you get
reimbursement here, if you get reimbursement in tuition fees,
which
you have left to pay, if you yourself fall ill for
more than a month
or your family member falls ill for
more than a month, then the
expenses incurred on your tuition fees will be borne by the company. The
second is bail bond. The
meaning of bail here is that if you
commit any such bailable offence due to which
you are arrested and detained.  If you
go abroad, then the expenses incurred for that will be
a specific amount. I will
mention it further and will tell you. Up
to that specific amount, you will be compensated.
Under Passer Protection also, your tuition fees will be
reimbursed if your spouse falls
ill or dies. Let's
talk about a short visit, suppose
you fall ill for a day or more
and one of your immediate family members
wants to come there. If you want to
come abroad, then a first class train
ticket or an economy class air ticket will be
given to them, plus there will be a provision for stay there.
Two options are given, Gold Plan and
Gold Plus Plan. Let's talk about Gold
Plan, here you will have medical
expenses which you will insure, right
brother,
you can take insurance cover between Rs. 10000 to Rs. 5 lakh, so
whatever cover you take, it will be useful in your medical
expenses. In this policy,
you will also get dental expenses up to Rs. 50,000 in
which there will also be a deductible of $.
Repatriation of  Remains will
come under your medical expenses only.
You can claim
up to Rs. 000,000 in baggage loss, apart from this you can claim up to Rs. 5 lakh.
Apart from this, there
is a claim of $5000 in personal accident. Up to $ lakh in personal liabilities.
If you cause an accident to
a third party, then the expenses incurred
there will be compensated up to $ lakh.
You will get a benefit of up to $55,000 for bail bond.
You will also get a benefit of up to $500 for two-way compassionate visit. You will get a
benefit of $500 in study interruption. You will
get a benefit of $10,000 in sponsor protection. If the passport is lost, you will
get a benefit of up to $200.
To make a new passport or duplicate passport,
talk about option number two of
Gold Plus benefit. There you will get the
benefits of Gold,
along with that you will get one more
additional benefit like
treatment for mental illness.  Disorders will
also be covered here for up to 000, which is
mental or depression or whatever is related to it,
those expenses are not covered in Gold,
but here they will be covered up to 000, in-
patient medical expenses related
to pregnancy, in which there will be a waiting period of 10 years and 10 months,
so here you will
get a benefit of $500, plus if there is
any injury due to sports, then that will
also be counted in your medical, whereas
this was not counted in Gold, and there will
also be a benefit of 000 for cancer screening
and child care benefit
in this, now for how long you want to take this policy from 0000 to
5 lakh dollars, you can
take it for one month, you
can take it for two months, you can
also take it for three months, for four months, 6 months, 9 months, 12 months,
456 days,
546 days, 636 days and a maximum of 700
days,
now the accident there  It happens and
if there is death in an accident then
100% money is given, otherwise if there is any disability then
what percentage will be given for that is
mentioned here. You should have a
proposal form, university
enrollment form, passport copy
and visa copy. You can purchase this policy with these documents.
Here you
can also understand the process of claiming. You will get cashless treatment and
reimbursement as well. If you want to
take cashless treatment
due to hospitalization or bail bond, first of all you will have to
inform the ESP to the assistant service provider. They will help you
in your validation and authorization
and after that they will get your claim passed.
If you want reimbursement then
you will have to inform the assistant service provider after taking all the bills etc. You will have to
mail it to the assistant service provider.
You
can send all the documents through email and the address and email are
mentioned below in the video. You
can see which email ID or which number you have to
contact and there you will get
your reimbursement in 15 days.  The
address related to the payment claim is
of Gurugram and you can see that right now,
speaking of Gurugram, the address of Gurugram
is mentioned here and for medical or travel
assistant, you have been given the LF number of USA,
Rest of the World and
National as well. Email
ID is also mentioned
ICICIlordf.com, you can also email on this. Let's
talk about general exclusions, if
a physician has advised you not to travel,
still you are travelling, then it will
not be covered. If any
harm is caused due to terrorist activity, then it will not be covered. If any war-
like situation occurs, then the
claim arising in that will not be covered.
If someone harms himself
or is involved in criminal activities or
someone harms himself due to drinking
or
harms himself after consuming drugs, then there are
general exclusions in all these things. If
any harm is caused due to these, then it will
not be covered in this particular
policy.  Talking about the exclusions of the policy, if the
main
objective of the Trip Tech plan you are taking is only to get medical treatment, then
it will not be covered. If there is a pre-existing
condition, then it will
not be covered in the policy.
If you want to get cosmetic or plastic surgery done due to an accident or any other reason, then
it will not be covered in it. And if your passport is
lost because you either
reached late or you were detained
by the customs or the police and
due to the delay you did not reach there
or there is a loss of passport, in that
case you will be covered in this policy.
If you are going abroad to study, then you should definitely take the Student Travel Insurance Policy. It would be
better to purchase it from India itself because you will get it at a very cheap price
and it will cover overseas and will
also cover worldwide. There
is also an option of excluding US and Canada in this policy and
you are also covered for worldwide, so
you can also get cover for different time periods, from ₹0,000 to ₹5 lakh. And if the policy  If you
want to purchase from me then you
can contact me on 0940 3412 P You
can also contact me and if you liked the video then please share it with
me.